In some natures there are no half-tones; nothing but raw primary colours. John Bodman was a man who was always at one extreme or the other. This probably would have mattered little had he not married a wife whose nature was an exact duplicate of his own.  Doubtless there exists in this world precisely the right woman for any given man to marry and vice versa; but when you consider that a human being has the opportunity of being acquainted with only a few hundred people, and out of the few hundred that there are but a dozen or less whom he knows intimately, and out of the dozen, one or two friends at most, it will easily be seen, when we remember the number of millions who inhabit this world, that probably, since the earth was created, the right man has never yet met the right woman. The mathematical chances are all against such a meeting, and this is the reason that divorce courts exist. Marriage at best is but a compromise, and if two people happen to be united who are of an uncompromising nature there is trouble.  In the lives of these two young people there was no middle distance. The result was bound to be either love or hate, and in the case of Mr. and Mrs. Bodman it was hate of the most bitter and arrogant kind.  In some parts of the world incompatibility of temper is considered a just cause for obtaining a divorce, but in England no such subtle distinction is made, and so until the wife became criminal, or the man became both criminal and cruel, these two were linked together by a bond that only death could sever. Nothing can be worse than this state of things, and the matter was only made the more hopeless by the fact that Mrs. Bodman lived a blameless life, and her husband was no worse, but rather better, than the majority of men. Perhaps, however, that statement held only up to a certain point, for John Bodman had reached a state of mind in which he resolved to get rid of his wife at all hazards. If he had been a poor man he would probably have deserted her, but he was rich, and a man cannot freely leave a prospering business because his domestic life happens not to be happy.  When a man's mind dwells too much on any one subject, no one can tell just how far he will go. The mind is a delicate instrument, and even the law recognises that it is easily thrown from its balance. Bodman's friends--for he had friends--claim that his mind was unhinged; but neither his friends nor his enemies suspected the truth of the episode, which turned out to be the most important, as it was the most ominous, event in his life.  Whether John Bodman was sane or insane at the time he made up his mind to murder his wife, will never be known, but there was certainly craftiness in the method he devised to make the crime appear the result of an accident. Nevertheless, cunning is often a quality in a mind that has gone wrong.  Mrs. Bodman well knew how much her presence afflicted her husband, but her nature was as relentless as his, and her hatred of him was, if possible, more bitter than his hatred of her. Wherever he went she accompanied him, and perhaps the idea of murder would never have occurred to him if she had not been so persistent in forcing her presence upon him at all times and on all occasions. So, when he announced to her that he intended to spend the month of July in Switzerland, she said nothing, but made her preparations for the journey. On this occasion he did not protest, as was usual with him, and so to Switzerland this silent couple departed.  There is an hotel near the mountain-tops which stands on a ledge over one of the great glaciers. It is a mile and a half above the level of the sea, and it stands alone, reached by a toilsome road that zigzags up the mountain for six miles. There is a wonderful view of snow-peaks and glaciers from the verandahs of this hotel, and in the neighbourhood are many picturesque walks to points more or less dangerous.  John Bodman knew the hotel well, and in happier days he had been intimately acquainted with the vicinity. Now that the thought of murder arose in his mind, a certain spot two miles distant from this inn continually haunted him. It was a point of view overlooking everything, and its extremity was protected by a low and crumbling wall. He arose one morning at four o'clock, slipped unnoticed out of the hotel, and went to this point, which was locally named the Hanging Outlook. His memory had served him well. It was exactly the spot, he said to himself. The mountain which rose up behind it was wild and precipitous. There were no inhabitants near to overlook the place. The distant hotel was hidden by a shoulder of rock. The mountains on the other side of the valley were too far away to make it possible for any casual tourist or native to see what was going on on the Hanging Outlook. Far down in the valley the only town in view seemed like a collection of little toy houses.  One glance over the crumbling wall at the edge was generally sufficient for a visitor of even the strongest nerves. There was a sheer drop of more than a mile straight down, and at the distant bottom were jagged rocks and stunted trees that looked, in the blue haze, like shrubbery.  'This is the spot,' said the man to himself, 'and to-morrow morning is the time.'  John Bodman had planned his crime as grimly and relentlessly, and as coolly, as ever he had concocted a deal on the Stock Exchange. There was no thought in his mind of mercy for his unconscious victim. His hatred had carried him far.  The next morning after breakfast, he said to his wife: 'I intend to take a walk in the mountains. Do you wish to come with me?'  'Yes,' she answered briefly.  'Very well, then,' he said; 'I shall be ready at nine o'clock.'  'I shall be ready at nine o'clock,' she repeated after him.  At that hour they left the hotel together, to which he was shortly to return alone. The spoke no word to each other on their way to the Hanging Outlook. The path was practically level, skirting the mountains, for the Hanging Outlook was not much higher above the sea than the hotel.  John Bodman had formed no fixed plan for his procedure when the place was reached. He resolved to be guided by circumstances. Now and then a strange fear arose in his mind that she might cling to him and possibly drag him over the precipice with her. He found himself wondering whether she had any premonition of her fate, and one of his reasons for not speaking was the fear that a tremor in his voice might possibly arouse her suspicions. He resolved that his action should be sharp and sudden, that she might have no chance either to help herself or to drag him with her. Of her screams in that desolate region he had no fear. No one could reach the spot except from the hotel, and no one that morning had left the house, even for an expedition to the glacier--one of the easiest and most popular trips from the place.  Curiously enough, when they came within sight of the Hanging Outlook, Mrs. Bodman stopped and shuddered. Bodman looked at her through the narrow slits of his veiled eyes, and wondered again if she had any suspicion. No one can tell, when two people walk closely together, what unconscious communication one mind may have with another.  'What is the matter?' he asked gruffly. 'Are you tired?'  'John,' she cried, with a gasp in her voice, calling him by his Christian name for the first time in years, 'don't you think that if you had been kinder to me at first, things might have been different?'  'It seems to me,' he answered, not looking at her, 'that it is rather late in the day for discussing that question.'  'I have much to regret,' she said quaveringly. 'Have you nothing?'  'No,' he answered.  'Very well,' replied his wife, with the usual hardness returning to her voice. 'I was merely giving you a chance. Remember that.'  Her husband looked at her suspiciously.  'What do you mean?' he asked, 'giving me a chance? I want no chance nor anything else from you. A man accepts nothing from one he hates. My feeling towards you is, I imagine, no secret to you. We are tied together, and you have done your best to make the bondage insupportable.'  'Yes,' she answered, with her eyes on the ground, 'we are tied together--we are tied together!'  She repeated these words under her breath as they walked the few remaining steps to the Outlook. Bodman sat down upon the crumbling wall. The woman dropped her alpenstock on the rock, and walked nervously to and fro, clasping and unclasping her hands. Her husband caught his breath as the terrible moment drew near.  'Why do you walk about like a wild animal?' he cried. 'Come here and sit down beside me, and be still.'  She faced him with a light he had never before seen in her eyes--a light of insanity and of hatred.  'I walk like a wild animal,' she said, 'because I am one. You spoke a moment ago of your hatred of me; but you are a man, and your hatred is nothing to mine. Bad as you are, much as you wish to break the bond which ties us together, there are still things which I know you would not stoop to. I know there is no thought of murder in your heart, but there is in mine. I will show you, John Bodman, how much I hate you.'  The man nervously clutched the stone beside him, and gave a guilty start as she mentioned murder.  'Yes,' she continued, 'I have told all my friends in England that I believed you intended to murder me in Switzerland.'  'Good God!' he cried. 'How could you say such a thing?'  'I say it to show how much I hate you--how much I am prepared to give for revenge. I have warned the people at the hotel, and when we left two men followed us. The proprietor tried to persuade me not to accompany you. In a few moments those two men will come in sight of the Outlook. Tell them, if you think they will believe you, that it was an accident.'  The mad woman tore from the front of her dress shreds of lace and scattered them around. Bodman started up to his feet, crying, 'What are you about?' But before he could move toward her she precipitated herself over the wall, and went shrieking and whirling down the awful abyss.  The next moment two men came hurriedly round the edge of the rock, and found the man standing alone. Even in his bewilderment he realised that if he told the truth he would not be believed.  On one of the upper branches of the Congo river lived an ancient and aristocratic family of hippopotamuses, which boasted a pedigree dating back beyond the days of Noah--beyond the existence of mankind--far into the dim ages when the world was new.  They had always lived upon the banks of this same river, so that every curve and sweep of its waters, every pit and shallow of its bed, every rock and stump and wallow upon its bank was as familiar to them as their own mothers. And they are living there yet, I suppose.  Not long ago the queen of this tribe of hippopotamuses had a child which she named Keo, because it was so fat and round. Still, that you may not be misled, I will say that in the hippopotamus language 'Keo,' properly translated, means 'fat and lazy' instead of fat and round. However, no one called the queen's attention to this error, because her tusks were monstrous long and sharp, and she thought Keo the sweetest baby in the world.  He was, indeed, all right for a hippopotamus. He rolled and played in the soft mud of the river bank, and waddled inland to nibble the leaves of the wild cabbage that grew there, and was happy and contented from morning till night. And he was the jolliest hippopotamus that ancient family had ever known. His little red eyes were forever twinkling with fun, and he laughed his merry laugh on all occasions, whether there was anything to laugh at or not.  Therefore the black people who dwelt in that region called him 'Ippi'--the jolly one, although they dared not come anigh him on account of his fierce mother, and his equally fierce uncles and aunts and cousins, who lived in a vast colony upon the river bank.  And while these black people, who lived in little villages scattered among the trees, dared not openly attack the royal family of hippopotamuses, they were amazingly fond of eating hippopotamus meat whenever they could get it. This was no secret to the hippopotamuses. And, again, when the blacks managed to catch these animals alive, they had a trick of riding them through the jungles as if they were horses, thus reducing them to a condition of slavery.  Therefore, having these things in mind, whenever the tribe of hippopotamuses smelled the oily odor of black people they were accustomed to charge upon them furiously, and if by chance they overtook one of the enemy they would rip him with their sharp tusks or stamp him into the earth with their huge feet.  It was continual warfare between the hippopotamuses and the black people.  Gouie lived in one of the little villages of the blacks. He was the son of the chief's brother and grandson of the village sorcerer, the latter being an aged man known as the 'the boneless wonder,' because he could twist himself into as many coils as a serpent and had no bones to hinder his bending his flesh into any position. This made him walk in a wabbly fashion, but the black people had great respect for him.  Gouie's hut was made of branches of trees stuck together with mud, and his clothing consisted of a grass mat tied around his middle. But his relationship to the chief and the sorcerer gave him a certain dignity, and he was much addicted to solitary thought. Perhaps it was natural that these thoughts frequently turned upon his enemies, the hippopotamuses, and that he should consider many ways of capturing them.  Finally he completed his plans, and set about digging a great pit in the ground, midway between two sharp curves of the river. When the pit was finished he covered it over with small branches of trees, and strewed earth upon them, smoothing the surface so artfully that no one would suspect there was a big hole underneath. Then Gouie laughed softly to himself and went home to supper.  That evening the queen said to Keo, who was growing to be a fine child for his age:  'I wish you'd run across the bend and ask your Uncle Nikki to come here. I have found a strange plant, and want him to tell me if it is good to eat.'  The jolly one laughed heartily as he started upon his errand, for he felt as important as a boy does when he is sent for the first time to the corner grocery to buy a yeast cake.  'Guk-uk-uk-uk! guk-uk-uk-uk!' was the way he laughed; and if you think a hippopotamus does not laugh this way you have but to listen to one and you will find I am right.  He crawled out of the mud where he was wallowing and tramped away through the bushes, and the last his mother heard as she lay half in and half out of the water was his musical 'guk-uk-uk-uk!' dying away in the distance.  Keo was in such a happy mood that he scarcely noticed where he stepped, so he was much surprised when, in the middle of a laugh, the ground gave way beneath him, and he fell to the bottom of Gouie's deep pit. He was not badly hurt, but had bumped his nose severely as he went down; so he stopped laughing and began to think how he should get out again. Then he found the walls were higher than his head, and that he was a prisoner.  So he laughed a little at his own misfortune, and the laughter soothed him to sleep, so that he snored all through the night until daylight came.  When Gouie peered over the edge of the pit next morning he exclaimed:  'Why, 'tis Ippi--the Jolly One!'  Keo recognized the scent of a black man and tried to raise his head high enough to bite him. Seeing which Gouie spoke in the hippopotamus language, which he had learned from his grandfather, the sorcerer.  'Have peace, little one; you are my captive.'  'Yes; I will have a piece of your leg, if I can reach it,' retorted Keo; and then he laughed at his own joke: 'Guk-uk-uk-uk!'  But Gouie, being a thoughtful black man, went away without further talk, and did not return until the following morning. When he again leaned over the pit Keo was so weak from hunger that he could hardly laugh at all.  'Do you give up?' asked Gouie, 'or do you still wish to fight?'  'What will happen if I give up?' inquired Keo.  The black man scratched his woolly head in perplexity.  'It is hard to say, Ippi. You are too young to work, and if I kill you for food I shall lose your tusks, which are not yet grown. Why, O Jolly One, did you fall into my hole? I wanted to catch your mother or one of your uncles.'  'Guk-uk-uk-uk!' laughed Keo. 'You must let me go, after all, black man; for I am of no use to you!'  'That I will not do,' declared Gouie; 'unless,' he added, as an afterthought, 'you will make a bargain with me.'  'Let me hear about the bargain, black one, for I am hungry,' said Keo.  'I will let your go if you swear by the tusks of your grandfather that you will return to me in a year and a day and become my prisoner again.'  The youthful hippopotamus paused to think, for he knew it was a solemn thing to swear by the tusks of his grandfather; but he was exceedingly hungry, and a year and a day seemed a long time off; so he said, with another careless laugh:  'Very well; if you will now let me go I swear by the tusks of my grandfather to return to you in a year and a day and become your prisoner.'  Gouie was much pleased, for he knew that in a year and a day Keo would be almost full grown. So he began digging away one end of the pit and filling it up with the earth until he had made an incline which would allow the hippopotamus to climb out.  Keo was so pleased when he found himself upon the surface of the earth again that he indulged in a merry fit of laughter, after which he said:  'Good-by, Gouie; in a year and a day you will see me again.'  Then he waddled away toward the river to see his mother and get his breakfast, and Gouie returned to his village.  During the months that followed, as the black man lay in his hut or hunted in the forest, he heard at times the faraway 'Guk-uk-uk-uk!' of the laughing hippopotamus. But he only smiled to himself and thought: 'A year and a day will soon pass away!'  Now when Keo returned to his mother safe and well every member of his tribe was filled with joy, for the Jolly One was a general favorite. But when he told them that in a year and a day he must again become the slave of the black man, they began to wail and weep, and so many were their tears that the river rose several inches.  Of course Keo only laughed at their sorrow; but a great meeting of the tribe was called and the matter discussed seriously.  'Having sworn by the tusks of his grandfather,' said Uncle Nikki, 'he must keep his promise. But it is our duty to try in some way to rescue him from death or a life of slavery.'  To this all agreed, but no one could think of any method of saving Keo from his fate. So months passed away, during which all the royal hippopotamuses were sad and gloomy except the Jolly One himself.  Finally but a week of freedom remained to Keo, and his mother, the queen, became so nervous and worried that another meeting of the tribe was called. By this time the laughing hippopotamus had grown to enormous size, and measured nearly fifteen feet long and six feet high, while his sharp tusks were whiter and harder than those of an elephant.  'Unless something is done to save my child,' said the mother, 'I shall die of grief.'  Then some of her relations began to make foolish suggestions; but presently Uncle Nep, a wise and very big hippopotamus, said:  'We must go to Glinkomok and implore his aid.'  Then all were silent, for it was a bold thing to face the mighty Glinkomok. But the mother's love was equal to any heroism.  'I will myself go to him, if Uncle Nep will accompany me,' she said, quickly.  Uncle Nep thoughtfully patted the soft mud with his fore foot and wagged his short tail leisurely from side to side.  'We have always been obedient to Glinkomok, and shown him great respect,' said he. 'Therefore I fear no danger in facing him. I will go with you.'  All the others snorted approval, being very glad they were not called upon to go themselves.  So the queen and Uncle Nep, with Keo swimming between them, set out upon their journey. They swam up the river all that day and all the next, until they came at sundown to a high, rocky wall, beneath which was the cave where the might Glinkomok dwelt.  This fearful creature was part beast, part man, part fowl and part fish. It had lived since the world began. Through years of wisdom it had become part sorcerer, part wizard, part magician and part fairy. Mankind knew it not, but the ancient beasts knew and feared it.  The three hippopotamuses paused before the cave, with their front feet upon the bank and their bodies in the water, and called in chorus a greeting to Glinkomok. Instantly thereafter the mouth of the cave darkened and the creature glided silently toward them.  The hippopotamuses were afraid to look upon it, and bowed their heads between their legs.  'We come, O Glinkomok, to implore your mercy and friendly assistance!' began Uncle Nep; and then he told the story of Keo's capture, and how he had promised to return to the black man.  'He must keep his promise,' said the creature, in a voice that sounded like a sigh.  The mother hippopotamus groaned aloud.  'But I will prepare him to overcome the black man, and to regain his liberty,' continued Glinkomok.  Keo laughed.  'Lift your right paw,' commanded Glinkomok. Keo obeyed, and the creature touched it with its long, hairy tongue. Then it held four skinny hands over Keo's bowed head and mumbled some words in a language unknown to man or beast or fowl or fish. After this it spoke again in hippopotamese:  'Your skin has now become so tough that no man can hurt you. Your strength is greater than that of ten elephants. Your foot is so swift that you can distance the wind. Your wit is sharper than the bulthorn. Let the man fear, but drive fear from your own breast forever; for of all your race you are the mightiest!'  Then the terrible Glinkomok leaned over, and Keo felt its fiery breath scorch him as it whispered some further instructions in his ear. The next moment it glided back into its cave, followed by the loud thanks of the three hippopotamuses, who slid into the water and immediately began their journey home.  The mother's heart was full of joy; Uncle Nep shivered once or twice as he remembered a glimpse he had caught of Glinkomok; but Keo was as jolly as possible, and, not content to swim with his dignified elders, he dived under their bodies, raced all around them and laughed merrily every inch of the way home.  Then all the tribe held high jinks and praised the mighty Glinkomok for befriending their queen's son. And when the day came for the Jolly One to give himself up to the black man they all kissed him good-by without a single fear for his safety.  Keo went away in good spirits, and they could hear his laughing 'guk-uk-uk-uk!' long after he was lost in sight in the jungle.  Gouie had counted the days and knew when to expect Keo; but he was astonished at the monstrous size to which his captive had grown, and congratulated himself on the wise bargain he had made. And Keo was so fat that Gouie determined to eat him--that is, all of him he possibly could, and the remainder of the carcass he would trade off to his fellow villagers.  So he took a knife and tried to stick it into the hippopotamus, but the skin was so tough the knife was blunted against it. Then he tried other means; but Keo remained unhurt.  And now indeed the Jolly One laughed his most gleeful laugh, till all the forest echoed the 'guk-uk-uk-uk-uk!' And Gouie decided not to kill him, since that was impossible, but to use him for a beast of burden. He mounted upon Keo's back and commanded him to march. So Keo trotted briskly through the village, his little eyes twinkling with merriment.  The other blacks were delighted with Gouie's captive, and begged permission to ride upon the Jolly One's back. So Gouie bargained with them for bracelets and shell necklaces and little gold ornaments, until he had acquired quite a heap of trinkets. Then a dozen black men climbed upon Keo's back to enjoy a ride, and the one nearest his nose cried out:  'Run, Mud-dog--run!'  And Keo ran. Swift as the wind he strode, away from the village, through the forest and straight up the river bank. The black men howled with fear; the Jolly One roared with laughter; and on, on, on they rushed!  Then before them, on the opposite side of the river, appeared the black mouth of Glinkomok's cave. Keo dashed into the water, dived to the bottom and left the black people struggling to swim out. But Glinkomok had heard the laughter of Keo and knew what to do. When the Jolly One rose to the surface and blew the water from his throat there was no black man to be seen.  Keo returned alone to the village, and Gouie asked, with surprise:  'Where are my brothers:'  'I do not know,' answered Keo. 'I took them far away, and they remained where I left them.'  Gouie would have asked more questions then, but another crowd of black men impatiently waited to ride on the back of the laughing hippopotamus. So they paid the price and climbed to their seats, after which the foremost said:  'Run, mud-wallower--run!'  And Keo ran as before and carried them to the mouth of Glinkomok's cave, and returned alone.  But now Gouie became anxious to know the fate of his fellows, for he was the only black man left in his village. So he mounted the hippopotamus and cried:  'Run, river-hog--run!'  Keo laughed his jolly 'guk-uk-uk-uk!' and ran with the speed of the wind. But this time he made straight for the river bank where his own tribe lived, and when he reached it he waded into the river, dived to the bottom and left Gouie floating in the middle of the stream.  The black man began swimming toward the right bank, but there he saw Uncle Nep and half the royal tribe waiting to stamp him into the soft mud. So he turned toward the left bank, and there stood the queen mother and Uncle Nikki, red-eyed and angry, waiting to tear him with their tusks.  Then Gouie uttered loud screams of terror, and, spying the Jolly One, who swam near him, he cried:  'Save me, Keo! Save me, and I will release you from slavery!'  'That is not enough,' laughed Keo.  'I will serve you all my life!' screamed Gouie; 'I will do everything you bid me!'  'Will you return to me in a year and a day and become my captive, if I allow you to escape?' asked Keo.  'I will! I will! I will!' cried Gouie.  'Swear it by the bones of your grandfather!' commanded Keo, remembering that black men have no tusks to swear by.  And Gouie swore it by the bones of his grandfather.  Then Keo swam to the black one, who clambered upon his back again. In this fashion they came to the bank, where Keo told his mother and all the tribe of the bargain he had made with Gouie, who was to return in a year and a day and become his slave.  Therefore the black man was permitted to depart in peace, and once more the Jolly One lived with his own people and was happy.  When a year and a day had passed Keo began watching for the return of Gouie; but he did not come, then or ever afterwards.  For the black man had made a bundle of his bracelets and shell necklaces and little gold ornaments and had traveled many miles into another country, where the ancient and royal tribe of hippopotamuses was unknown. And he set up for a great chief, because of his riches, and people bowed down before him.  By day he was proud and swaggering. But at night he tumbled and tossed upon his bed and could not sleep. His conscience troubled him.  For he had sworn by the bones of his grandfather; and his grandfather had no bones. Two men in a smoking-room were talking of their private-school days. æAt our school,Æ said A., æwe had a ghostÆs footmark on the staircase. What was it like? Oh, very unconvincing. Just the shape of a shoe, with a square toe, if I remember right. The staircase was a stone one. I never heard any story about the thing. That seems odd, when you come to think of it. Why didnÆt somebody invent one, I wonder?Æ  æYou never can tell with little boys. They have a mythology of their own. ThereÆs a subject for you, by the wayùÆThe Folklore of Private SchoolsÆ.Æ  æYes; the crop is rather scanty, though. I imagine, if you were to investigate the cycle of ghost stories, for instance, which the boys at private schools tell each other, they would all turn out to be highly-compressed versions of stories out of books.Æ  æNowadays the Strand and PearsonÆs, and so on, would be extensively drawn upon.Æ  æNo doubt: they werenÆt born or thought of in my time. LetÆs see. I wonder if I can remember the staple ones that I was told. First, there was the house with a room in which a series of people insisted on passing a night; and each of them in the morning was found kneeling in a corner, and had just time to say, æIÆve seen it,Æ and died.Æ  æWasnÆt that the house in Berkeley Square?Æ  æI dare say it was. Then there was the man who heard a noise in the passage at night, opened his door, and saw someone crawling towards him on all fours with his eye hanging out on his cheek. There was besides, let me thinkùYes! the room where a man was found dead in bed with a horseshoe mark on his forehead, and the floor under the bed was covered with marks of horseshoes also; I donÆt know why. Also there was the lady who, on locking her bedroom door in a strange house, heard a thin voice among the bed-curtains say, æNow weÆre shut in for the night.Æ None of those had any explanation or sequel. I wonder if they go on still, those stories.Æ  æOh, likely enoughùwith additions from the magazines, as I said. You never heard, did you, of a real ghost at a private school? I thought not; nobody has that ever I came across.Æ  æFrom the way in which you said that, I gather that you have.Æ  æI really donÆt know; but this is what was in my mind. It happened at my private school thirty odd years ago, and I havenÆt any explanation of it.  æThe school I mean was near London. It was established in a large and fairly old houseùa great white building with very fine grounds about it; there were large cedars in the garden, as there are in so many of the older gardens in the Thames valley, and ancient elms in the three or four fields which we used for our games. I think probably it was quite an attractive place, but boys seldom allow that their schools possess any tolerable features.  æI came to the school in a September, soon after the year 1870; and among the boys who arrived on the same day was one whom I took to: a Highland boy, whom I will call McLeod. I neednÆt spend time in describing him: the main thing is that I got to know him very well. He was not an exceptional boy in any wayùnot particularly good at books or gamesùbut he suited me.  æThe school was a large one: there must have been from 120 to 130 boys there as a rule, and so a considerable staff of masters was required, and there were rather frequent changes among them.  æOne termùperhaps it was my third or fourthùa new master made his appearance. His name was Sampson. He was a tallish, stoutish, pale, black-bearded man. I think we liked him: he had travelled a good deal, and had stories which amused us on our school walks, so that there was some competition among us to get within earshot of him. I remember tooùdear me, I have hardly thought of it since then!ùthat he had a charm on his watch-chain that attracted my attention one day, and he let me examine it. It was, I now suppose, a gold Byzantine coin; there was an effigy of some absurd emperor on one side; the other side had been worn practically smooth, and he had had cut on itùrather barbarouslyùhis own initials, G.W.S., and a date, 24 July, 1865. Yes, I can see it now: he told me he had picked it up in Constantinople: it was about the size of a florin, perhaps rather smaller. æWell, the first odd thing that happened was this. Sampson was doing Latin grammar with us. One of his favourite methodsùperhaps it is rather a good oneùwas to make us construct sentences out of our own heads to illustrate the rules he was trying to make us learn. Of course that is a thing which gives a silly boy a chance of being impertinent: there are lots of school stories in which that happensùor anyhow there might be. But Sampson was too good a disciplinarian for us to think of trying that on with him. Now, on this occasion he was telling us how to express remembering in Latin: and he ordered us each to make a sentence bringing in the verb memini, æI remember.Æ Well, most of us made up some ordinary sentence such as æI remember my father,Æ or æHe remembers his book,Æ or something equally uninteresting: and I dare say a good many put down memino librum meum, and so forth: but the boy I mentionedùMcLeodùwas evidently thinking of something more elaborate than that. The rest of us wanted to have our sentences passed, and get on to something else, so some kicked him under the desk, and I, who was next to him, poked him and whispered to him to look sharp. But he didnÆt seem to attend. I looked at his paper and saw he had put down nothing at all. So I jogged him again harder than before and upbraided him sharply for keeping us all waiting. That did have some effect. He started and seemed to wake up, and then very quickly he scribbled about a couple of lines on his paper, and showed it up with the rest. As it was the last, or nearly the last, to come in, and as Sampson had a good deal to say to the boys who had written meminiscimus patri meo and the rest of it, it turned out that the clock struck twelve before he had got to McLeod, and McLeod had to wait afterwards to have his sentence corrected. There was nothing much going on outside when I got out, so I waited for him to come. He came very slowly when he did arrive, and I guessed there had been some sort of trouble.  æWell,Æ I said, æwhat did you get?Æ æOh, I donÆt know,Æ said McLeod, ænothing much: but I think SampsonÆs rather sick with me.Æ æWhy, did you show him up some rot?Æ æNo fear,Æ he said. æIt was all right as far as I could see: it was like this: MementoùthatÆs right enough for remember, and it takes a genitive,ùmemento putei inter quatuor taxos.Æ æWhat silly rot!Æ I said. æWhat made you shove that down? What does it mean?Æ æThatÆs the funny part,Æ said McLeod. æIÆm not quite sure what it does mean. All I know is, it just came into my head and I corked it down. I know what I think it means, because just before I wrote it down I had a sort of picture of it in my head: I believe it means æRemember the well among the fourÆùwhat are those dark sort of trees that have red berries on them?Æ æMountain ashes, I sÆpose you mean.Æ æI never heard of them,Æ said McLeod; æno, IÆll tell youùyews.Æ æWell, and what did Sampson say?Æ æWhy, he was jolly odd about it. When he read it he got up and went to the mantelpiece and stopped quite a long time without saying anything, with his back to me. And then he said, without turning round, and rather quiet, æWhat do you suppose that means?Æ I told him what I thought; only I couldnÆt remember the name of the silly tree: and then he wanted to know why I put it down, and I had to say something or other. And after that he left off talking about it, and asked me how long IÆd been here, and where my people lived, and things like that: and then I came away: but he wasnÆt looking a bit well.Æ  æI donÆt remember any more that was said by either of us about this. Next day McLeod took to his bed with a chill or something of the kind, and it was a week or more before he was in school again. And as much as a month went by without anything happening that was noticeable. Whether or not Mr. Sampson was really startled, as McLeod had thought, he didnÆt show it. I am pretty sure, of course, now, that there was something very curious in his past history, but IÆm not going to pretend that we boys were sharp enough to guess any such thing.  æThere was one other incident of the same kind as the last which I told you. Several times since that day we had had to make up examples in school to illustrate different rules, but there had never been any row except when we did them wrong. At last there came a day when we were going through those dismal things which people call Conditional Sentences, and we were told to make a conditional sentence, expressing a future consequence. We did it, right or wrong, and showed up our bits of paper, and Sampson began looking through them. All at once he got up, made some odd sort of noise in his throat, and rushed out by a door that was just by his desk. We sat there for a minute or two, and thenùI suppose it was incorrectùbut we went up, I and one or two others, to look at the papers on his desk. Of course I thought someone must have put down some nonsense or other, and Sampson had gone off to report him. All the same, I noticed that he hadnÆt taken any of the papers with him when he ran out. Well, the top paper on the desk was written in red inkùwhich no one usedùand it wasnÆt in anyoneÆs hand who was in the class. They all looked at itùMcLeod and allùand took their dying oaths that it wasnÆt theirs. Then I thought of counting the bits of paper. And of this I made quite certain: that there were seventeen bits of paper on the desk, and sixteen boys in the form. Well, I bagged the extra paper, and kept it, and I believe I have it now. And now you will want to know what was written on it. It was simple enough, and harmless enough, I should have said.  æ æSi tu non veneris ad me, ego veniam ad te,Æ which means, I suppose, æIf you donÆt come to me, IÆll come to you.Æ Æ  æCould you show me the paper?Æ interrupted the listener.  æYes, I could: but thereÆs another odd thing about it. That same afternoon I took it out of my lockerùI know for certain it was the same bit, for I made a finger-mark on itùand no single trace of writing of any kind was there on it. I kept it, as I said, and since that time I have tried various experiments to see whether sympathetic ink had been used, but absolutely without result.  æSo much for that. After about half an hour Sampson looked in again: said he had felt very unwell, and told us we might go. He came rather gingerly to his desk and gave just one look at the uppermost paper: and I suppose he thought he must have been dreaming: anyhow, he asked no questions.  æThat day was a half-holiday, and next day Sampson was in school again, much as usual. That night the third and last incident in my story happened.  æWeùMcLeod and Iùslept in a dormitory at right angles to the main building. Sampson slept in the main building on the first floor. There was a very bright full moon. At an hour which I canÆt tell exactly, but some time between one and two, I was woken up by somebody shaking me. It was McLeod; and a nice state of mind he seemed to be in. æCome,Æ he said,ùÆcome! thereÆs a burglar getting in through SampsonÆs window.Æ As soon as I could speak, I said, æWell, why not call out and wake everybody up?Æ æNo, no,Æ he said, æIÆm not sure who it is: donÆt make a row: come and look.Æ Naturally I came and looked, and naturally there was no one there. I was cross enough, and should have called McLeod plenty of names: onlyùI couldnÆt tell whyùit seemed to me that there was something wrongùsomething that made me very glad I wasnÆt alone to face it. We were still at the window looking out, and as soon as I could, I asked him what he had heard or seen. æI didnÆt hear anything at all,Æ he said, æbut about five minutes before I woke you, I found myself looking out of this window here, and there was a man sitting or kneeling on SampsonÆs window-sill, and looking in, and I thought he was beckoning.Æ æWhat sort of man?Æ McLeod wriggled. æI donÆt know,Æ he said, æbut I can tell you one thingùhe was beastly thin: and he looked as if he was wet all over: and,Æ he said, looking round and whispering as if he hardly liked to hear himself, æIÆm not at all sure that he was alive.Æ  æWe went on talking in whispers some time longer, and eventually crept back to bed. No one else in the room woke or stirred the whole time. I believe we did sleep a bit afterwards, but we were very cheap next day.  æAnd next day Mr. Sampson was gone: not to be found: and I believe no trace of him has ever come to light since. In thinking it over, one of the oddest things about it all has seemed to me to be the fact that neither McLeod nor I ever mentioned what we had seen to any third person whatever. Of course no questions were asked on the subject, and if they had been, I am inclined to believe that we could not have made any answer: we seemed unable to speak about it.  æThat is my story,Æ said the narrator. æThe only approach to a ghost story connected with a school that I know, but still, I think, an approach to such a thing.Æ  The sequel to this may perhaps be reckoned highly conventional; but a sequel there is, and so it must be produced. There had been more than one listener to the story, and, in the latter part of that same year, or of the next, one such listener was staying at a country house in Ireland. One evening his host was turning over a drawer full of odds and ends in the smoking-room. Suddenly he put his hand upon a little box. æNow,Æ he said, æyou know about old things; tell me what that is.Æ My friend opened the little box, and found in it a thin gold chain with an object attached to it. He glanced at the object and then took off his spectacles to examine it more narrowly. æWhatÆs the history of this?Æ he asked. æOdd enough,Æ was the answer. æYou know the yew thicket in the shrubbery: well, a year or two back we were cleaning out the old well that used to be in the clearing here, and what do you suppose we found?Æ æIs it possible that you found a body?Æ said the visitor, with an odd feeling of nervousness. æWe did that: but whatÆs more, in every sense of the word, we found two.Æ æGood Heavens! Two? Was there anything to show how they got there? Was this thing found with them?Æ æIt was. Amongst the rags of the clothes that were on one of the bodies. A bad business, whatever the story of it may have been. One body had the arms tight round the other. They must have been there thirty years or moreùlong enough before we came to this place. You may judge we filled the well up fast enough. Do you make anything of whatÆs cut on that gold coin you have there?Æ æI think I can,Æ said my friend, holding it to the light (but he read it without much difficulty); æit seems to be G.W.S., 24 July, 1865.Æ It was a Thursday, but it felt like a Monday to John. And John loved Mondays. He thrived at work. He dismissed the old clichÚ of dreading Monday mornings and refused to engage in water-cooler complaints about ôthe grindö and empty conversations that included the familiar parry ôHow was your weekend?ö ôToo short!ö. Yes, John liked his work and was unashamed.  I should probably get another latte. IÆve just been sitting here with this empty cup. But then IÆll start to get jittery. IÆll get a decaf. No, thatÆs stupid, it feels stupid to pay for a decaf. I canÆt justify that.   John was always impatient on the weekends; he missed the formal structure of the business week. When he was younger he used to stay late after school on Fridays and come in early on Mondays, a pattern his mother referred to with equal parts admiration and disdain as ôstudying overtime.ö  Jesus, IÆve written another loser.  Now, John spent his weekends doing yard work at the Tudor house Rebecca left him after their divorce. Rebecca, with her almond eyesùboth in shape and in colorùcould never be his enemy.  That barista keeps looking at me. SheÆll probably ask me to leave if I donÆt buy something. SheÆs kind of attractive. Not her hairùher hair seems stringyùbut her face is nice. I should really buy something.  Their divorce was remarkably amicable. In fact, John would often tell his parents, ôRebecca and I are better friends now than when we were married!ö In fact, John looked forward to the days when he and Rebecca, with their new partners, would reminisce about their marriage, seeing it in a positive light, like two mature adults.  Maybe IÆll just get a pumpkin-spice loaf. That way I can still sit here without going through a whole production of buying a coffee and giving my name and feeling like an asshole while it gets made.  But if John were being honest, the house did get lonely on the weekends. RebeccaÆs parents had been generous enough to leave John the house even though they had paid for it. John was still struggling to get his short-story writingùI mean, his paintingùcareer off the ground, and Rebecca and her family had been more than supportive, even during the breakup.  Maybe the baristaÆs looking at me because she thinks IÆm attractive. I am in my blue shirt. So she has stringy hair? Who am I to complain about stringy hair? Who do I think I am? Cary Grant?  And now John was doing temp work at the law firm of Fleurstein and Kaplowitz to get himself righted again. He had a strong six-month plan: he would save some money to pay RebeccaÆs parents back for the house and be able to take some time off to focus on his writingùon his painting. In a few months, he would be back on his feet, probably even engaged to someone new. Maybe even that barista. Yes, almost paradoxically, temp work provided John with the stability he craved.  This is shit. It is utter shit.  Actually, in moments of great self-reflection, John hated his work. Who was he kidding? He was doing temp work. No one has ever liked temp work. It reinforced his feeling of instability, confirmed his cynical view of the job market, and took him away from the only thing he ever enjoyed doing, which was writing short storiesùI mean painting! Painting! John enjoyed painting!  I think I have to pee.  And John was a great painter. close dialog To get more of the latest stories from The New Yorker, sign up for our newsletter.  Enter your e-mail address. Get access.  Literally every single person on line for the bathroom looks homeless. Maybe I can just go in and not touch anything. IÆll just lift the seat up with my shoe.  John often wondered how Steve Bowman from college was having so much success while John was stuck doing temp work in a futile attempt to pay back RebeccaÆs passive-aggressive parents for a house he hadnÆt even wanted them to buy. And Steve Bowman was a talentless hack who even admitted to John that he only writesùpaints!ùso that he can ôbag women.ö He actually said ôbag women.ö But Rebecca thinks heÆs ôinterestingö and that they could ôhave a real life together.ö I hope they both die of cancer. What did John have with Rebecca? How was that not ôrealö? Maybe if RebeccaÆs parents had let John breathe instead of forcing their hypocritical Christian ôvaluesö down his throat every chance they got, their relationship would have been more ôreal.ö Good luck, Steve Bowman. I hope you like having a mother-in-law with no boundaries.  I think I will get another latte. That barista is so sexy. IÆd love to pull her stringy hair while we have sex on my floor.  John would often go to Rebecca and SteveÆs new house in the middle of the night and just stare in their window.  She probably has a back tattoo. So slutty.  John would secretly hope to see Steve and Rebecca fighting. He would fantasize about seeing their silhouettes through the window, Rebecca throwing the telephone at Steve and him ducking but it still hitting him in the head. John would get aroused by this fantasy.  IÆll say something cool, like ôThe coffeeÆs not the only thing hot in here.ö And sheÆll probably be like, ôI get off at seven.ö And IÆll probably say something like ôI donÆt have a real job, so any timeÆs good for me.ö Jesus, who am I kidding? IÆm a loser. She would never like me. Even a stringy-haired barista with a slutty back tattoo would never like me.  But, of course, John never saw anything in Steve and RebeccaÆs window. He thought of urinating in a glass bottle and throwing it through their window, but he couldnÆt even work up the courage to do that. He was a loser who couldnÆt even commit a petty act of vandalism.  He was a dumb dumb stupid dumb writerùpainter!ùwho couldnÆt even afford an office, so he wroteùpainted!ùin a Starbucks because he got fired from Fleurstein and Kaplowitz for making copies of his storiesùpaintings!ùwhen he was supposed to be copying legal briefs for those corrupt corporate shylocks.  And Rebecca would never come back to him and no one would ever love him and he was going to die fat and bald and alone and miserable in the ugly house his in-laws bought to suffocate and kill him!  Maybe IÆll get a tea. I like that hibiscus one. ItÆs sweet but not too sweet. ItÆs nice. ItÆs a nice flavor.  And maybe I will get a slice of that pumpkin loaf. I think I had it before. I think I definitely liked it. I think it must be seasonal. I havenÆt seen it in a while.  IÆll eat and drink and then get back to work. Everything seems to be flowing well. It was a little tough getting into it but now itÆs really flowing. ItÆs weird how I do thatùhow I think I canÆt write something and suddenly IÆm carried away and then I canÆt stop writing. I think IÆm too hard on myself. I think I punish myself for no reason. But I think IÆm really hitting my stride now. IÆll just get that tea. That nice hibiscus tea.  And then get back to work. Knowing that Mrs. Mallard was afflicted with a heart trouble, great care was taken to break to her as gently as possible the news of her husband's death. It was her sister Josephine who told her, in broken sentences; veiled hints that revealed in half concealing. Her husband's friend Richards was there, too, near her. It was he who had been in the newspaper office when intelligence of the railroad disaster was received, with Brently Mallard's name leading the list of 'killed.' He had only taken the time to assure himself of its truth by a second telegram, and had hastened to forestall any less careful, less tender friend in bearing the sad message.  She did not hear the story as many women have heard the same, with a paralyzed inability to accept its significance. She wept at once, with sudden, wild abandonment, in her sister's arms. When the storm of grief had spent itself she went away to her room alone. She would have no one follow her.  There stood, facing the open window, a comfortable, roomy armchair. Into this she sank, pressed down by a physical exhaustion that haunted her body and seemed to reach into her soul.  She could see in the open square before her house the tops of trees that were all aquiver with the new spring life. The delicious breath of rain was in the air. In the street below a peddler was crying his wares. The notes of a distant song which some one was singing reached her faintly, and countless sparrows were twittering in the eaves.  There were patches of blue sky showing here and there through the clouds that had met and piled one above the other in the west facing her window.  She sat with her head thrown back upon the cushion of the chair, quite motionless, except when a sob came up into her throat and shook her, as a child who has cried itself to sleep continues to sob in its dreams.  She was young, with a fair, calm face, whose lines bespoke repression and even a certain strength. But now there was a dull stare in her eyes, whose gaze was fixed away off yonder on one of those patches of blue sky. It was not a glance of reflection, but rather indicated a suspension of intelligent thought.  There was something coming to her and she was waiting for it, fearfully. What was it? She did not know; it was too subtle and elusive to name. But she felt it, creeping out of the sky, reaching toward her through the sounds, the scents, the color that filled the air.  Now her bosom rose and fell tumultuously. She was beginning to recognize this thing that was approaching to possess her, and she was striving to beat it back with her will--as powerless as her two white slender hands would have been. When she abandoned herself a little whispered word escaped her slightly parted lips. She said it over and over under hte breath: 'free, free, free!' The vacant stare and the look of terror that had followed it went from her eyes. They stayed keen and bright. Her pulses beat fast, and the coursing blood warmed and relaxed every inch of her body.  She did not stop to ask if it were or were not a monstrous joy that held her. A clear and exalted perception enabled her to dismiss the suggestion as trivial. She knew that she would weep again when she saw the kind, tender hands folded in death; the face that had never looked save with love upon her, fixed and gray and dead. But she saw beyond that bitter moment a long procession of years to come that would belong to her absolutely. And she opened and spread her arms out to them in welcome.  There would be no one to live for during those coming years; she would live for herself. There would be no powerful will bending hers in that blind persistence with which men and women believe they have a right to impose a private will upon a fellow-creature. A kind intention or a cruel intention made the act seem no less a crime as she looked upon it in that brief moment of illumination.  And yet she had loved him--sometimes. Often she had not. What did it matter! What could love, the unsolved mystery, count for in the face of this possession of self-assertion which she suddenly recognized as the strongest impulse of her being!  'Free! Body and soul free!' she kept whispering.  Josephine was kneeling before the closed door with her lips to the keyhold, imploring for admission. 'Louise, open the door! I beg; open the door--you will make yourself ill. What are you doing, Louise? For heaven's sake open the door.'  'Go away. I am not making myself ill.' No; she was drinking in a very elixir of life through that open window.  Her fancy was running riot along those days ahead of her. Spring days, and summer days, and all sorts of days that would be her own. She breathed a quick prayer that life might be long. It was only yesterday she had thought with a shudder that life might be long.  She arose at length and opened the door to her sister's importunities. There was a feverish triumph in her eyes, and she carried herself unwittingly like a goddess of Victory. She clasped her sister's waist, and together they descended the stairs. Richards stood waiting for them at the bottom.  Some one was opening the front door with a latchkey. It was Brently Mallard who entered, a little travel-stained, composedly carrying his grip-sack and umbrella. He had been far from the scene of the accident, and did not even know there had been one. He stood amazed at Josephine's piercing cry; at Richards' quick motion to screen him from the view of his wife.  When the doctors came they said she had died of heart disease--of the joy that kills. 
